[
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "In Python, a variable that stores text is called a ________.",
      "options": [
        "list",
        "tuple",
        "string",
        "dictionary"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "A Python ________ is an ordered and mutable collection of values.",
      "options": [
        "set",
        "list",
        "tuple",
        "dictionary"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "A ________ in Python is used to store key-value pairs.",
      "options": [
        "list",
        "dictionary",
        "tuple",
        "set"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "An unordered collection of unique values in Python is called a ________.",
      "options": [
        "list",
        "tuple",
        "set",
        "dictionary"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "A Python list is defined using ________ brackets.",
      "options": [
        "curly",
        "square",
        "round",
        "angle"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "A tuple in Python is ________, meaning it cannot be changed once created.",
      "options": [
        "mutable",
        "ordered",
        "immutable",
        "unordered"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "Python stores numbers as _______, _______, or _______ types.",
      "options": [
        "int, float, complex",
        "list, tuple, dictionary",
        "string, set, tuple",
        "char, string, boolean"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "The function used to find the data type of a variable in Python is ________.",
      "options": [
        "data()",
        "typeof()",
        "type()",
        "datatype()"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "The output of type(3.14) in Python will be ________.",
      "options": [
        "int",
        "float",
        "complex",
        "string"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "In a Python dictionary, values are accessed using their ________.",
      "options": [
        "position",
        "index",
        "key",
        "value"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    }
]
  